[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to section 3
您好，欢迎来到第3节
of lesson 1.
第一课
In this part of the lesson we'll be talking about functional interfaces and
在本课的这一部分中，我们将讨论函数式接口和
their definition.
他们的定义。
These are places where you can use Lambda expressions
这些是您可以使用Lambda表达式的地方
in your code. In the previous part of the lesson
在您的代码中。在本课程的前一部分
I described how a Lambda expression is an anonymous function
我描述了Lambda表达式如何是匿名函数
and by that I meant it's like a method,
我的意思是，这就像一种方法，
but one that is not associated with a class.
但与类无关的人。
That's okay; we have a method,
没关系;我们有一种方法
an anonymous function but not associated with a class. The issue here is that
匿名函数，但不与类关联。这里的问题是
Java is a strongly typed language, so we must make sure that whatever we’re using
Java是一种强类型语言，因此我们必须确保无论使用什么
has a type associated with it. In the case of a Lambda expression,
具有与之关联的类型。对于Lambda表达式，
although it represents a method and it's an anonymous function
虽然它代表一个方法，并且是一个匿名函数
there must be a type for the Lambda expression,
Lambda表达式必须有一个类型，
and to simplify this
并简化这个
what we have said with JDK 8 is that
我们在JDK 8中所说的是
you can use a Lambda expression wherever the
您可以在任何地方使用Lambda表达式
type that's being used is
使用的类型是
a functional interface.
函数式接口。
A functional interface is one has a single
一个函数式接口就是一个有一个
abstract method. Because it has a single
抽象方法。因为它有一个
abstract method we can easily map
我们可以轻松映射的抽象方法
the Lambda expression to be the implementation
Lambda表达式作为实现
of that abstract method, so that
这种抽象方法，
in effect, the compiler
实际上，编译器
and the runtime is generating an object of
并且运行时正在生成一个对象
that type using the Lambda expression to represent the method.
使用Lambda表达式表示该方法的类型。
But, and this is very important, even though
但是，这非常重要，即使
there is this idea of a type associated
有这种类型的想法
there is no class, so there's no object associated
没有类，所以没有对象
with the Lambda expression directly. It’s a kind of strange situation, where
直接使用Lambda表达式。这是一种奇怪的情况
it has a type but no object and we'll talk more about this
它有一个类型但没有对象，我们将进一步讨论
as we go through the rest of this particular lesson.
当我们完成本节课的其余部分时。
Let's go through the real
让我们来看看真实的
definition of a functional interface and make sure we
函数式接口的定义，并确保我们
understand exactly what that means. The first thing is that it has to be
确切了解这意味着什么。第一件事是必须
an interface. This might seem like a little bit of
接口。这似乎有点
an obvious thing when I say it's functional interface
当我说它是函数式接口时，这是显而易见的事情
but I also said that it has a single abstract method.
但我也说过，它只有一个抽象方法。
Some people suggest that, well if it only needs to have a single
有人建议，如果只需要一个
abstract method, could I not create an abstract
抽象方法，我不能创建一个抽象
class which only has one abstract method defined in it.
类，其中仅定义了一个抽象方法。
In theory you could but for JDK 8
从理论上讲，您可以选择JDK 8
we don't support that. So functional interface, where you can use a Lambda
我们不支持。所以函数式接口，您可以在其中使用Lambda
expression,
表达，
has to be an interface. It also has to have
必须是一个接口。它也必须有
one and only one abstract method because remember the
一种也是唯一的一种抽象方法，因为请记住
Lambda expression provides an implementation of that abstract method.
Lambda表达式提供了该抽象方法的实现。
If we had more than one abstract method we wouldn't know
如果我们有多个抽象方法，我们将不知道
which particular method the Lambda expression related to
Lambda表达式与哪种特定方法有关
and we would be left with one or more methods that don't have an implementation.
我们将剩下一个或多个没有实现的方法。
So one abstract method, Lambda expression,
因此，一种抽象方法Lambda表达式
maps to the implementation of that method. Now
映射到该方法的实现。现在
before JDK 8 if you looked at a method
在JDK 8之前，如果您看过一种方法
interface definition it was very easy to see if it was going to be a
接口定义，很容易看出它是否将成为
functional interface.
函数式接口。
That was one that had only one method.
那是只有一种方法的方法。
In JDK 8
在JDK 8中
we also introduced a couple of other new features, and a couple of new changes to the
我们还引入了其他一些新功能，并对
syntax
句法
of the language. One of those was specifically so that we could
语言。其中之一是为了使我们能够
make it easier to extend the existing Collections API
使扩展现有Collections API更加容易
which relies a lot on interfaces without breaking backwards compatibility.
它在很大程度上依赖于接口而不会破坏向后兼容性。
So to do that we introduced the idea of the default method,
为此，我们引入了默认方法的思想，
the default method is simply one that can be placed
默认方法只是可以放置的方法
in an interface which is an abstract
在一个抽象的界面中
because it has an implementation associated with it.
因为它具有与之关联的实现。
The idea that is if you're using an old version
这个想法是，如果您使用的是旧版本
of a class which implemented the interface before these methods were
在实现这些方法之前实现接口的类
added, when the compiler tries to resolve one of those methods,
添加了，当编译器尝试解析这些方法之一时，
rather than going to the the old version of the class and saying, oh
而不是去上课的旧版本然后说，哦
that method doesn't exist, I can’t compile, it goes to the
该方法不存在，我无法编译，它转到
class and says, oh that method doesn't exist, goes back to the interface
类并说，哦，该方法不存在，请返回接口
and finds the default implementation to use for that.
并找到用于此目的的默认实现。
This is way we have added multiple inheritance of behavior to
这样，我们就将行为的多重继承添加到了
Java
爪哇
in the same way we would have multiple inheritance of types.
以同样的方式，我们将拥有多个类型的继承。
Now because we can now have
现在，因为我们现在可以拥有
behavior in an interface, it also makes sense
界面中的行为，这也很有意义
to allow static methods to be added to interfaces as well.
也允许将静态方法添加到接口。
Those are the two changes that we need to understand.
这些是我们需要了解的两个变化。
And, in order to
并且，为了
have the compiler check whether what we think is a functional
让编译器检查我们认为是否功能正常
interface
接口
really is, there is an annotation that could be added,
确实是，可以添加一个注释，
@FunctionalInterface, and the compiler will then check there is only
@FunctionalInterface，然后编译器将检查是否只有
one abstract method in that particular interface.
该特定接口中的一种抽象方法。
Let's look at some examples
让我们看一些例子
of interfaces that we already have in Java before JDK 8
JDK 8之前我们在Java中已经拥有的接口
that can use Lambda expressions
可以使用Lambda表达式
to represent them. FileFilter is a good example because it has a single method,
代表他们。 FileFilter是一个很好的例子，因为它只有一个方法，
accept, which returns a boolean, takes a file.
accept，它返回一个布尔值，并接收一个文件。
ActionListener, same thing, has a single method
同样，ActionListener具有单个方法
ActionPerformed and callable has a single action
可执行且可调用的动作只有一个
call. All of those existed in Java before JDK 8
呼叫。所有这些都在JDK 8之前存在于Java中
and we can use Lambda expressions for those if we want to
如果需要，我们可以对这些使用Lambda表达式
because they are functional interfaces.
因为它们是函数式接口。
Let's have a look at some other interfaces and decide whether
让我们看看其他一些接口，并确定是否
they're actually function or not.
它们实际上是否起作用。
Here we have the runnable interface and that has one method:
这里我们有可运行的接口，并且有一个方法：
public abstract void run. The question is,
公共抽象无效运行。问题是，
is this in fact a functional interface? The answer is
这实际上是函数式接口吗？答案是
fairly straightforward because, yes, we only have one
非常简单，因为是的，我们只有一个
abstract method. I tried to make it as obvious as possible here, actually defined as
抽象方法。我试图使它在这里尽可能明显，实际上定义为
abstract.
抽象。
There’s one abstract method in this interface and therefore
这个介面中只有一种抽象方法，因此
it is a functional interface. Let's look at
它是一个函数式接口。让我们来看看
a slightly more complicated one. This is the predicate interface,
稍微复杂一点。这是 Predicate 接口，
which is one of the new java.util.function
这是新的java.util.function之一
interfaces and we'll talk more about this later on. This has
介面，我们稍后会详细讨论。这有
five methods in it. Three of those methods
五种方法。其中三种方法
are default methods and then we have a static method
是默认方法，然后有一个静态方法
and then we also have one method called test,
然后我们还有一种叫做test的方法
which returns a boolean. If we want to determine whether this is a functional
返回一个布尔值。如果我们要确定这是否是功能
interface or not
是否界面
obviously we need to decide whether all those methods count
显然，我们需要决定所有这些方法是否有价值
in terms of abstract methods are not. I said that,
就抽象方法而言不是。我说了，
in terms of default methods, these don't count.
就默认方法而言，这些不算在内。
Because these have an implementation associated with them,
由于这些具有与之相关的实现，
by definition they are not abstract. Similarly,
根据定义，它们不是抽象的。同样，
the static method isEquals has
静态方法isEquals具有
an implementation associated with it; therefore by default
与之相关的实现；因此默认
it is not an abstract method. That leaves us with just
它不是抽象方法。剩下的只是
one method, boolean test, which
一种方法，布尔测试，
is abstract, therefore we have one abstract method
是抽象的，因此我们有一种抽象方法
in our interface and therefore it is a functional
在我们的界面中，因此它是一个功能
interface. One last method that we’ll have a look at, because
接口。我们要看的最后一种方法，因为
this is a little more tricky this one. Comparator.
这个比较棘手。比较器。
Comparator has some static methods; has some default methods
比较器有一些静态方法。有一些默认方法
which I've left out because we’ve agreed that those don't count.
我之所以忽略了这一点，是因为我们同意这些都不算在内。
There are still two methods in this interface:
此界面中仍然有两种方法：
there’s a compare method and
有一个比较方法，
there’s an equal method. You would think,
有一个平等的方法。你会想，
based on this, that this was not a functional interface.
基于此，这不是函数式接口。
But there is one rule that I haven't told you about
但是有一条我没有告诉过你的规则
which is still applicable in terms
在条款上仍然适用
of determining whether this is a functional interface. In the case of this
确定这是否是一个函数式接口。在这种情况下
one
一
the equals method is actually
equals方法实际上是
implicitly inherited from the object class.
从对象类隐式继承。
Remember object is the superclass of all classes and we're actually
记住对象是所有类的超类，我们实际上是
inheriting the equals class from the object class.
从对象类继承equals类。
Because of that it doesn't count in terms of
因此，它不计入
an abstract method for this particular interface
此特定接口的抽象方法
and so we still only have one abstract method which is the compare method
因此，我们仍然只有一种抽象方法，即比较方法
and so this is in fact a functional interface. Just as an aside,
因此这实际上是一个函数式接口。顺便说一句，
I did look at why the equals method was
我确实看过为什么equals方法是
included in this particular interface, because
包含在此特定界面中，因为
other interfaces don't include this and I needed to understand why that was the
其他接口不包括此接口，我需要了解为什么这是
case.
案件。
It turns out the only reason that the equals method is defined
事实证明，定义了equals方法的唯一原因
in this interface is because it is inherited from
在这个界面中是因为它是从
the object class is so that some different documentation
对象类是一些不同的文档
can be included in the javadoc above that particular method
可以包含在该特定方法上方的javadoc中
when it's used in terms of compare. That’s just
用于比较时。那只是
an interesting aside. When we want to use a Lambda expression
有趣的一面。当我们想使用Lambda表达式时
we can either use it assigning it to a
我们可以使用它将其分配给
variable or we can use it as a parameter to a method.
变量，或者我们可以将其用作方法的参数。
In the case of the first example here, I have a callable c
在这里的第一个示例中，我有一个可调用的c
(remember callable has a single abstract method, therefore
（记住callable有一个抽象方法，因此
we can represent it by a Lambda expression)
我们可以用Lambda表达式表示它）
and the Lambda expression is simply to call process. The
Lambda表达式只是调用过程。的
call method of the callable doesn't have any parameters
可调用对象的调用方法没有任何参数
so we use empty brackets.
因此我们使用空括号。
Same thing applies in terms of a method parameter,
方法参数同样适用
so in this example I’m creating a new thread object and
所以在这个例子中，我创建了一个新的线程对象，
I'm passing the Lambda expression as the parameter to the constructor.
我将Lambda表达式作为参数传递给构造函数。
Again, we want to use the same approach so we have a
同样，我们希望使用相同的方法，因此我们有一个
Lambda expression that represents the run method
代表run方法的Lambda表达式
will be process and it doesn't take any parameters
将是过程，它不需要任何参数
as arguments so we use empty brackets. That’s just
作为参数，因此我们使用空括号。那只是
a way of how we can use them both as variable assignment
一种如何将它们都用作变量分配的方式
and when we pass parameters to methods. To summarize section 3,
以及当我们将参数传递给方法时。总结第3节，
we can use a Lambda expression anywhere the type
我们可以在任何类型的地方使用Lambda表达式
of where we want to use it is
我们要使用它的地方是
a functional interface. Remember a functional interface
函数式接口。记住函数式接口
is one that has only one abstract method. For JDK 8 that
是只有一种抽象方法的一种。对于JDK 8
doesn't mean that it only has one method. If it has default methods,
并不意味着它只有一种方法。如果具有默认方法，
if it has static methods, if has methods that are inherited from
如果具有静态方法，如果具有从其继承的方法
the object class then they don't count. In terms of what the Lambda expression
对象类，则它们不计算在内。关于Lambda的表达方式
represents,
代表，
is it is the implementation of that single
是那单的实现吗
abstract method of that functional interface, so the
该函数式接口的抽象方法，因此
abstract method we’re going to use the
我们将使用抽象方法
Lambda expression represents the implementation of that.
Lambda表达式表示该实现。
And that is the end
到此为止
of section 3 of this lesson
本课程第3部分